<resources>
    <string name="app_name">QuizApp</string>
    <string name="opening_text1">Can you save a life?  \nIn an emergency, when every second is critical, would you know what to do?</string>
    <string name="opening_text2">Would you be able to save someones life?</string>
    <string name="swipe">Swipe up to continue</string>
    <string name="why">Why should I know how to perform CPR (Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation)?</string>
    <string name="whyAnswer">
        According to recent statistics sudden cardiac arrest is rapidly becoming the leading cause of death in America.
        Once the heart ceases to function, a healthy human brain may survive without oxygen for up to 4 minutes without suffering any permanent damage.
        Unfortunately, a typical EMS response may take 6, 8 or even 10 minutes. \n\nIt is during those critical minutes that CPR can provide oxygenated blood to the victim\'s brain and the heart,
        dramatically increasing his chance of survival. And if properly instructed, almost anyone can learn and perform CPR.
    </string>

    <string name="time">
        <b>CPR TIME LINE</b>
        \n<u>0-4 mins:</u> brain damage unlikely
        \n<u>4-6 mins:</u> brain damage possible
        \n<u>6-10 mins:</u> brain damage probable
        \n<u>over 10 mins:</u> probable brain death
    </string>

    <string name="quiz">Let\'s make a quick test to figure out, whether you would know what to do in this situation!</string>

    <string name="namehint">Please enter your name!</string>
    <string name="name">Name:</string>


    <!--questions-->
    <string name="q1">1. If you find someone collapsed, what is the first thing you should do?</string>
    <string name="a1">Try and wake the person up</string>
    <string name="b1">Call an ambulance</string>
    <string name="c1">Check for danger</string>
    <string name="d1">Check for breathing</string>

    <string name="q2">2. How should you open an airway in an unconscious casualty?</string>
    <string name="a2">Move the tongue with your fingers</string>
    <string name="b2"> Tilt the head back &amp; lift the chin</string>
    <string name="c2"> Tilt the head to the side</string>
    <string name="d2"> Tilt the head forwards</string>

    <string name="q3">3. How long should you check for breathing for?</string>
    <string name="a3">15 seconds</string>
    <string name="b3">5 seconds</string>
    <string name="c3">10 seconds</string>
    <string name="d3">20 seconds</string>

    <string name="q4">4. If someone isn\'t breathing, what is the first thing you should do?</string>
    <string name="a4">Setup an AED (Automated External Defibrillator)</string>
    <string name="b4">Call an ambulance</string>
    <string name="c4">Give 2 rescue breaths</string>
    <string name="d4">Give 30 chest compressions</string>

    <string name="q5">5. On an adult casualty, what is the ratio of chest compressions to rescue breaths?</string>
    <string name="a5">15 : 2</string>
    <string name="b5">30 : 2</string>
    <string name="c5">30 : 5</string>
    <string name="d5">1 : 5</string>

    <string name="q6">6. When should you stop doing CPR?</string>
    <string name="a6">The situation suddenly becomes too dangerous</string>
    <string name="b6">After 5 minutes</string>
    <string name="c6">You become too exhausted to continue</string>
    <string name="d6">The casualty shows signs of life: coughing, breathing etc.</string>

    <string name="q7">7. What rate of chest compressions should you aim for?</string>
    <string name="a7">70 - 100</string>
    <string name="b7">100 – 120</string>
    <string name="c7">80 - 90</string>
    <string name="d7">120 – 140</string>

    <string name="q8">8. You have to undertaken formal first aid training in order to perform CPR</string>
    <string name="a8">True</string>
    <string name="b8">False</string>

    <string name="q9">9. The casualty is likely to recover whilst you are performing CPR</string>
    <string name="a9">True</string>
    <string name="b9">False</string>

    <string name="button">check results</string>

    <string name="read">If you want to further your knowledge on this important topic, you can read the following brief lesson:</string>

    <string name="good">Congratulations! \nYou have the potential of a real hero!</string>
    <string name="okay">Good job! \nThank you for challenging yourself and taking this quiz! There\'s a little room for further improvement.</string>
    <string name="poor">You could have done it better!\nThank you for challenging yourself! Please read the lesson and retake your quiz</string>

    <!--lesson-->

    <string name="lessonTitle">How to perform CPR?</string>
    <string name="DRABC">
        You can use the mnemonic <b>DR ABC</b> to remember what to do:
        \n<li><b>Danger:</b> Check for any dangers to yourself.</li>
        \n<li><b>Response:</b> Check for a response from the casualty. Shout and gently shake them on the shoulders.</li>
        \n<li><b>Airway:</b> Kneel by the casualty’s head and open their airway by tilting their head backwards</li>
        \n<li><b>Breathing:</b> Place your ear above their mouth and look at their chest. Check for normal breathing (regular breaths) for up to 10 seconds</li>
        \n<li><b>Compressions:</b> If the casualty is not breathing, you should call an ambulance and start chest compressions.\n</li>
        \nOnce you’ve found someone isn’t breathing, you should start CPR by administering 30 chest compressions.
        Interlock your hands and place them in the middle of the person’s chest and push down 30 times.
        You should aim for a depth equal to a third the depth of their chest.
        \nYou do not need to check for a pulse, as this often wastes valuable time.
        If a public defibrillator is available, then it should be sent for.
        \nAfter 30 chest compressions, you should give 2 rescue breaths.
        Tilt the casualty’s head backwards, make a seal over their mouth and breath in twice.
        Each breath should only last about one second so as not to over inflate their lungs.
        \nYou should aim for a rate of 100 – 120 chest compressions a minute.
        Remember you don’t need to have undertaken formal first aid training in order to perform CPR!
        \n\nWill the casualty wake up?
        \n\nUnfortunately this is very unlikely to happen.
        By doing chest compressions, you are taking over the job of the casualty’s heart (which has stopped) by forcibly compressing it.
        In effect, you are acting as a life-support machine for the person.
        \nIn order for the heart to be restarted,
        it may require an electrical shock from a defibrillator or drugs given by a paramedic/doctor.
        CPR on its own is very unlikely to restart someone’s heart.
        \nHowever, good quality chest compressions will significantly increases the chance of the defibrillator being able to restart the heart.
        \n\nYou should only stop doing CPR if:
        \n\n<li>A defibrillator arrives and is about to be used</li>
        \n<li>The casualty shows signs of life: coughing, breathing etc.</li>
        \n<li>You are asked to stop by a healthcare professional (ambulance crew etc.)</li>
        \n<li>You become too exhausted to continue</li>
        \n<li>The situation suddenly becomes too dangerous</li>
        \n\nIdeally, you should only carry out CPR for a couple of minutes before swapping with someone else.
        This is to ensure that the chest compressions remain of good quality.
    </string>
    
    <string name="learnMore">
        Thank you for taking this quiz! It\'s important to remember that you don\'t need to have undertaken formal first aid training in order to perform CPR.
        In case of cardiac arrest, the survival of someone can depend on receiving CPR from you.
        This person could be even your loved one, whose life needs to be saved.
        Let\'s spread the word about the importance of CPR and increase awareness in your local communities.
    </string>

    <string name="sources">
        Sources:
        \nhttp://www.firstaidforfree.com
        \nhttp://www.whatiscpr.info
        \nhttps://www.firstaidweb.com
    </string>


</resources>
